JEFFERSON ARBOLEDA

Madrid, Spain

(+34) 678 20 83 13 * me@jarboleda.me * https://www.jarboleda.me/ * LinkedIn * GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Bachelor's degree in computer engineering and master's in computer engineering (Data Science). I manage a team of 30+ consultants working in 10+ IT projects. Previously, I worked as a business analyst for Amadeus, in the travel industry. Professional Scrum Product Owner, Microsoft Data Analyst Associate and preparing for PMP exam.

EXPERIENCE

ALTEN SPAIN MADRID, SPAIN

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

JAN 2021 - PRESENT

- Initiated, managed, and monitored IT projects and services (€1.5M turnover). Customers: Bank of Spain, National Institute of Cybersecurity, Ministries (Financial and Civil Service, Territorial Policy).
- Studied business opportunities based on RFPs, competitors, background with the customer, and predicted success rate, writing technical and economical bids for suitable opportunities.
- Business development: led meetings with key clients, identified their needs and provided solutions and services.
- Built dashboards to track the progress and KPIs of projects, using Power BI and various data sources.
- Managed 30+ consultants in 10+ projects, following up on their needs and career progression.
- Managed the cost and budget of my unit: P&L, profitability. Used Excel and Power BI to monitor personal targets.
- Negotiated, acquired, and deployed software licenses from international SW providers for my customers.
- Worked closely with transversal teams, being the leading POC for all actions: Legal, Billing, Recruiting, HR.

Competencies: Accounting, Hiring, Bidding, Negotiation, Excel, Power BI, Jira, Remedy, Word, PowerPoint.

ALTEN FRANCE NICE, FRANCE

BUSINESS ANALYST (AMADEUS, MOBILITY AND INSURANCE)

OCT 2017 - JAN 2021

- Collaborated with stakeholders to gather business requirements and translate them into working IT solutions, achieving a 100% volume increase in a fast-paced B2B migration context (Expedia.com, Priceline.com).
- Travelled with business team for pre-sales purposes (Priceline.com, US), creating dashboards with visualizations about the product and deep diving on its capabilities.
- Gathered data insights to drive prioritization of items in the team's backlog, using internal APIs and Python.
- Was the facilitator of the maintenance team for eight months, achieving over the target on opened records by the end of year, and taking ownership of maintenance tasks for two different products.

Competencies: Python/SQL, Splunk, API, C++, Excel, Jira, Scrum, Kanban, Specifications writing, Functional testing.

TCSET ALBACETE, SPAIN

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

FEB 2015 - SEP 2016

- Managed the full cycle of 12 projects, from gathering requirements to maintenance and customer training.
- Optimized SQL data handling to improve catalog updates over +100k products for our own e-commerce portal.
- Reduced incoming weekly tickets by 40% by creating customer ready documentation about our products.
- Reduced downtime to virtually zero by re-engineering and simplifying company's processes.
- Managed domains owned by the company (100+) and migrations between services providers.

Competencies: SQL, PHP, JavaScript, CSS/sass, Bash, Magento, Jira, SDLC, Product Ownership.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CASTILLA-LA MANCHA

ALBACETE, SPAIN

MASTER'S IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING (DATA SCIENCE)

ALBACETE, SPAIN

2017

University of Castilla-La Mancha

2011 – 2015

DEGREE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

CERTIFICATIONS

- MICROSOFT CERTIFIED DATA ANALYST ASSOCIATE. CREDENTIAL ID 1038-9708.
- SCRUM.ORG: PROFESSIONAL PRODUCT OWNER I. CREDENTIAL ID 737419.
- PMP 35 HOURS EXAM PREPARATION COURSE.

LANGUAGES

SPANISH (NATIVE); ENGLISH (C1 – CAMBRIDGE CAE: CERTIFICATE IN ADVANCED ENGLISH, 2017); FRENCH (CONVERSANT).